
export const quizQuestions_9 = {
  questions: [
    {
      question: 'In React functional components, what is the purpose of the useState hook?',
      choices: ['To connect to an external API', 'To manage the component’s internal state', 'To handle form submissions', 'To render components conditionally'],
      correctAnswer: 'To manage the component’s internal state',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'How do functional components in React handle lifecycle methods like componentDidMount?',
      choices: ['Using the componentDidMount method', 'With the useEffect hook', 'Lifecycle methods are not available in functional components', 'Through class inheritance'],
      correctAnswer: 'With the useEffect hook',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'What is the primary benefit of using the useCallback hook in a React functional component?',
      choices: ['To call functions as callbacks', 'To prevent unnecessary re-renders of child components', 'To fetch data asynchronously', 'To manage component state'],
      correctAnswer: 'To prevent unnecessary re-renders of child components',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'Why is it recommended to avoid inline function definitions in JSX in React functional components?',
      choices: ['It leads to a higher memory usage', 'Inline functions are slower', 'It can lead to unnecessary re-renders', 'Inline functions are deprecated in React'],
      correctAnswer: 'It can lead to unnecessary re-renders',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'How can you conditionally apply classes to an element in a React functional component?',
      choices: ['Using the useState hook', 'With a ternary operator in the className attribute', 'By manipulating the DOM directly', 'This is not possible in React'],
      correctAnswer: 'With a ternary operator in the className attribute',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'What is a common use case for using the useRef hook in React functional components?',
      choices: ['To store the component’s state', 'To interact with the DOM directly', 'To perform deep comparison of props', 'To create a reference to another component'],
      correctAnswer: 'To interact with the DOM directly',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'How do you fetch data in a React functional component?',
      choices: ['Using the componentDidMount method', 'With the fetchData hook', 'Using the useEffect hook', 'Data fetching is not possible in functional components'],
      correctAnswer: 'Using the useEffect hook',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'What does it mean when a React functional component is described as “pure”?',
      choices: ['It uses React.PureComponent', 'It doesn’t cause any side effects', 'It only accepts pure functions as props', 'It renders the same output given the same props'],
      correctAnswer: 'It renders the same output given the same props',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'In React, how can you improve the performance of a list rendered by a functional component?',
      choices: ['By using the useMemo hook', 'With the shouldComponentUpdate method', 'By always forcing the component to update', 'Performance improvement is not possible for lists'],
      correctAnswer: 'By using the useMemo hook',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'What is the role of the key prop in a list of elements rendered in a React functional component?',
      choices: ['It’s used for accessibility purposes', 'To uniquely identify each list item', 'It’s mandatory for styling the list', 'Keys play no role in functional components'],
      correctAnswer: 'To uniquely identify each list item',
    },
    
    
  ],
}